准备好过圣诞了吗  孩子们
Ready for Christmas, kids?
好了船长
Aye, aye, Captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye, aye, Captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
这里是海绵宝宝圣诞特辑
It's the SpongeBob Christmas Special
海绵宝宝
圣诞特辑
这里是恩斯诺
And now, direct from Encino
有请全美最爱的海盗
America's favorite pirate
及海绵宝宝粉丝俱乐部的主席
and president of the SpongeBob SquarePants Fan Club
海盗派斯
Patchy the Pirate
派斯
嗨
Hi
我是海盗派斯
I'm Patchy the Pirate
海绵宝宝粉丝俱乐部的主席
president of the SpongeBob SquarePants Fan Club
舒服多了
That's better
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas
说得对  波蒂
That's right, Potty
现在就是圣诞节
It is Christmas
七大洋里最好的东西
And there ain't nothing better in the seven seas
非裤头村的圣诞节莫属
than a Bikini Bottom Christmas
真是一年中最神奇的时刻
It sure is a magical time of year
海绵宝宝现在肯定是在
Why I'll bet old SpongeBob is gearing up
为迎接圣诞老人做准备
for Santa Claus right now
确实是
I sure am
欢迎圣诞老人
我准备好了
I'm ready
对无脊椎动物来说还挺不错
Not bad for a creature with no vertebrae
我看派大星兄弟肯定在做他那份装饰
And I'm sure our pal Patrick
is doing his share of the decorating
我也在为圣诞节做准备
I, too, am also preparing for Christmas
面粉
还没烤的饼干面团
Unbaked cookie dough
波蒂想吃饼干面团
Potty want cookie dough
别过来
No
饼干
Cookie
波蒂
Potty
别过来
No
饼干
Cookie
给我滚开
Get out of here
饼干
Cookie
波蒂
Potty
给我舔一口
Give us a lick
快滚  你个鸡毛掸子
Back off, you flying freak
快说为什么
Clarify, please
这饼干糊是给孩子们的
This here cookie dough is for the children
不是给烦人鹦鹉的
not for pesky parrots
啥东西
What's that?
三声铃声
Three bells
都知道三声铃声什么意思吧
Well, we all know what three bells means
免费冰淇淋
Free ice cream
错了  笨蛋
No, you silly livers
错
No
有人落海了
Man overboard?
我才不理你
You, I'm ignoring
错了
No
读粉丝来信的时间到了
It's time to open fan letters
给你
Here you go
谢谢  波蒂
Thank you, Potty
好
Yeah
行了波蒂
Okay, Potty
谢谢你
thank you
快给我啊你  傻鸟
Come on, give it, you birdbrain
死鸟别吵
Quiet, you infernal bird
这封寄给我们的信是来自
This letter comes to us from
已隐藏姓名与地址
Name and address withheld
他写道
And he writes
亲爱的海绵宝宝
"Dear SpongeBob
我今年十岁了
"I am ten years old
想知道你是不是跟我一样喜欢圣诞节
"and I was wondering if
you like Christmas as much as I do
真诚的
Sincerely yours"
已隐藏姓名与地址
Name and address withheld
这问题问得好
A very good question
可是你们知道
But you know
裤头村本来是不过圣诞节的吗
they didn't always
celebrate Christmas in Bikini Bottom
真没过吗
They didn't?
对的  害我脖子疼的死鸟
No, sir, my fine-feathered little neck pain
从前有一段时间
There was a time
裤头村里没一个人听说过有圣诞节
when no one had even heard of
Christmas in Bikini Bottom
谁想来听
Who wants to hear
海绵宝宝第一次过圣诞节的故事
the story of SpongeBob's very first Christmas?
波蒂
Potty?
你把我饼干面团都吃掉了
You ate all me cookie dough
那好吧
Oh, well
节目开始
On with the show
什么圣诞节
导演
翻译: 1440kHz
编剧
分镜总监
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
今天我要偷偷接近过去
Today I'm going sneak up
用超级机密空手道招数来偷袭珊迪
and get that Sandy with a super-sneaky karate move
她这是在搞什么邪恶的把戏
What diabolical act is she committing now?
着火了
Fire
珊迪  不要慌
Don't worry, Sandy
我来了
I'm coming
珊迪快后退
Stand back, Sandy
着火了
Fire
所以说没有着火
So, I guess there's no fire?
你到底是哪根筋不对  海绵宝宝
What in the name of the Alamo
is wrong with you, SpongeBob?
难道你从来就没见过圣诞树吗
Ain't you never seen a Christmas tree before?
什么圣诞
Christmas who?
什么
What?
连什么是圣诞都没听说过
Y'all never heard of Christmas?
是你在德州的朋友吗
Is she a friend from Texas?
才不是
No
你居然从来没听说过
I can't believe y'all haven't heard about
圣诞节
Christmas
再多跟我讲点这个
Tell me more about this
圣诞节吧
Christmas
就这样
And so
珊迪叙述了橡皮糖和口笛的神奇传说
Sandy wove a magical tale of
gumdrops and penny whistles
提到了做玩具的精灵和会飞的驯鹿
She told of toy-making elves and flying reindeer
不过最棒的是
But best of all
她还提到了那个
she told of the one they call
圣诞老人
Santa Claus
蟹堡王
然后大家都会假装喜欢水果蛋糕
and everyone pretends to like the fruitcake
哈欠
Yawn
不过最棒的地方就是
But the best part is
可以写信给这个叫圣诞老人的
you can write a letter to this guy Santa Claus
告诉他你想要什么东西
and tell him what you want
等他过来
and when he comes
就会把东西给你
he brings it to you
就跟灯神一个样
Just like a genie
虽然不知道你们旱鸭子在想什么
I don't know about you lubbers
不过只要有哪个谁白送免费玩意的
but any fella who's giving away free stuff
那个谁就会是我的朋友
is a friend o' mine
这就对了  蟹老板
That's the spirit, Mr. Krabs
给你
Here you go
你可以开始写信了
You can get started on your letter
该不会真的会有人过
I can't believe anybody would celebrate
让个潜行犯闯进家里送礼的节日
a holiday where a jolly prowler breaks into your house
and leaves gifts
跟灯神一个样
Like a genie
安静  章鱼哥
Pipe down, Squidward
我要集中精神
I'm trying to concentrate
这东西简直就是一张空白支票
This thing's as good as a blank check
还是圣诞老人第一国家银行发行的
direct from the First National Bank of Santa Claus
烦人
Ah, brother
行
Yeah
那好  下一个是谁
Okay, who's next?
我  我
Me, me
给你  派大星
Here you go, Patrick
这张纸上没有字
There's no words on this paper
当然还没
Not yet
写字用的棍子
A writing stick
来吧  章鱼哥
Come on, Squidward
写封信
write a letter
海绵宝宝  别这么幼稚行不
SpongeBob, grow up, will you?
没人会因为我写了封破信
No one's going to give me a gift
就给我礼物
just because I write them a stupid letter
海绵宝宝  我把纸给撕破了
SpongeBob, I ripped my paper
能再来一张吗
Could I have another one?
可以  兄弟
Sure, buddy
给你
here you go
来写吧  章鱼
Okey-dokey, Squid
哥
ward
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
谢谢
Thanks
亲爱的圣
"Dear San"
怎么又来
Not again
派大星过来
Here, Patrick
看我写
watch me
亲爱的圣诞老人
"Dear Santa
你是不是要问我这个圣诞节要什么
"What do I want for Christmas, you may ask?
我只想要让你来跟裤头村的各位见面
"All I want is for you
to visit the gentle folk here in Bikini Bottom
这就是我的愿望
That is my wish"
派大星
Patrick
我特别设计了这个装置
I designed this mechanism specifically
来把瓶子发射到海面上
to shoot bottles to the surface
所有人的希望就寄托在
The hopes of everyone rests on
这瓶子的成功首航上
the success of its maiden voyage
开火
Fire in the hole
圣诞老人
Santa
圣诞老人在哪
Where's Santa?
他得等平安夜才会来
He doesn't come till Christmas Eve
行了  小子
Okay, boy
我的要求
my demands
我是说  信
I mean letter
准备好要出发了
is ready to go
太棒了  蟹老板
Great, Mr. Krabs
你许愿要什么
What did you wish for?
小马
A pony
真就这样
Really?
身上驮着满满几袋子的钱
With saddle bags full of money
给你  海绵宝宝
Here you go, SpongeBob
你许愿要什么  派大星
What did you wish for, Patrick?
再来一张纸
Another piece of paper
你许愿要什么呢  小妹妹
And what did you wish for, little girl?
门牙
Front teeth
我要来顶新帽子
I could use a new hat
我要个新发型
I need a new hairstyle
我要来杯水洗牙
Another glass of water for my teeth
不好意思
Excuse me
借过
coming through
给我让开
out of the way
太棒了  章鱼哥
Great, Squidward
终于想好了
you finished
你愿望是什么
What's your wish?
我的愿望是裤头村的所有人
My wish is that the people of Bikini Bottom
都不要再去注意从这个这个傻子口中
will stop paying any attention to the inane drivel
接连不断冒出来的傻话
that is constantly streaming out
of this dunderhead's mouth
章鱼哥  也许圣诞老人会送我个词典
Squidward, maybe Santa will bring me a dictionary
这样我就能理解你刚说的话的意思了
so I can understand what you just said
好了  各位
Okay, everybody
既然我们已经召唤完圣诞老人了
we've got a lot to do
还有很多事情要做
now that we've summoned Santa Claus
我们必须要准备好迎接他的到来
We must ready ourselves for his arrival
蟹堡王
万岁
Hooray
精彩的节日马上就要浮现
It's shaping up to be a wonderful holiday
不是那普通平凡的每一天
Not your normal average everyday
好像有人砍了我珊瑚树
Sounds like someone felled my old coral tree
海绵宝宝  派大星
SpongeBob, Patrick
为何要害我苦
why'd you do this to me?
这世界好像充满爱意
The world feels like it's in loverly
快点滚  不然我就要弄伤你
Go away before I harm you bodily
这个圣诞节就是我的第一个圣诞节
This Christmas feels like
the very first Christmas to me
购物装饰大搞特搞  雪大片大片
There'll be shopping, decorating and plenty of snow
派大星  是谁在槲寄生下面
Hey, Patrick, who's that under the mistletoe?
彩灯
啥
What?
[ 圣诞习俗，在槲寄生下接吻 ]
谁
Who?
我
Me?
现在这么晚了  我得开溜
Would you look at the time, I should go
大家似乎都好像好兄弟
People seem a little more brotherly
水果蛋糕
我有一点薄礼想要给你
Here's a special something to you from me
就连垃圾在圣诞节闻着都甜蜜蜜
Even all the trash, on Christmas it smells so sweetly
这个圣诞节就是我的第一个圣诞节
This Christmas feels like
the very first Christmas to me
想干什么
What do you want?
不知我事业不绝
Can't you see that I'm busy?
快出来
Step outside
有东西要让你发掘
we've got something for you to see
海绵宝宝  快把这玩意都拆绝
SpongeBob, take this stuff down immediately
烤栗得烧伤三度失了味觉
Chestnuts roasting and burns in the third degree
今夜的一切都是那么欢悦
Tonight things are as good as they seem to be
树上的星终将标志美景无缺
A star on top will complete all the scenery
这个圣诞节就是我的第一个圣诞节
This Christmas feels like
the very first Christmas to me
这个圣诞节就是我的第一个圣诞节
This Christmas feels like
the very first Christmas to me
章鱼哥说对了吗
Is Squidward right?
海底究竟会不会有圣诞节
Can there be a Christmas under the sea?
不要走开
Stay tuned
你们可终于回来了
It's about time you got back
我可以继续讲完故事了
Now I can finish me story
海绵宝宝在送圣诞老人的最后一批信
So, SpongeBob was sending
the last of the letters to Santa
希望他能看懂葡萄牙语
I hope he can read Portuguese
行了  最后一封信送出去了
Well, that's the last letter
等下
Wait
章鱼哥还没有写信
Squidward hasn't written his letter yet
章鱼哥
Squidward
快写
hurry
章鱼哥
Squidward
快写
hurry
海绵宝宝  你在干什么
SpongeBob, what are you doing?
放心好了  章鱼哥
Don't worry, Squidward
我来帮你开头
I'll help you get started
亲爱的圣诞老人
"Dear Santa Claus"
海绵宝宝  算了吧你
SpongeBob, forget it
对  太正式了
Right, too formal
圣诞老人好
"Hi, Santa"
海绵宝宝  你别
SpongeBob, no
诞哥好
"Howdy, Claus"?
我才不给你幻想出来的东西写信
I'm not writing a letter to
a figment of your imagination
可是章鱼哥
But, Squidward
等圣诞老人来的时候
when Santa comes
就只有你没礼物了
you'll be the only one without a gift
海绵宝宝  我到底得说多少遍
SpongeBob, how many times do I have to say it?
我不相信有圣诞老人
I don't believe in Santa Claus
来吧  章鱼哥
Come on, Squid
你只要写封信就行了
all you have to do is write a letter
不会吃多大亏的
What have you got to lose?
我会亏自尊
My self-respect
亏理智
My sanity
亏午饭
My lunch
章鱼哥  写吧
Squidward, come on
写吧  章鱼哥
Come on, Squidward
别扫大家兴了
Don't be a party pooper
出来吧
Come on out
圣诞老人就一大骗子
Santa Claus is a big phony
海绵宝宝把你们都给耍了
SpongeBob has got you all fooled
写吧  章鱼哥
Come on, Squidward
来写吧
Come on
就让那些白痴熬一整夜吧
Those idiots are going to be up all night
我要睡个安稳觉
while I get a full night's sleep
圣诞老人今晚来
Santa's coming tonight, tonight
他会今晚来
Santa's coming tonight
圣诞老人今晚来
Santa's coming tonight, tonight
他会今晚来
Santa's coming tonight
大家一起唱
Come on, everybody
唱到圣诞老人来为止
let's sing till Santa gets here
圣诞老人今晚来
Santa's coming tonight, tonight
他会今晚来
Santa's coming tonight
圣诞老人今晚来
Santa's coming tonight, tonight
他会今晚来
Santa's coming tonight
圣诞老人今晚来
Santa's coming tonight, tonight
他会今晚来
Santa's coming tonight
圣诞老人在哪
Where's Santa?
他可能随时会来
He should be here any minute
圣诞老人今晚来
Santa's coming tonight, tonight
他会今晚来
Santa's coming
行了
Come on
老子受够了
Enough of this
感谢你的一派谎言  童话先生
Thanks for the lies, Mr. Fairytale
咱换别处浪费时间去
Let's go waste our time somewhere else
各位
Hey, guys
你们的圣诞精神都去哪了
where's your Christmas spirit?
他只是迟到了而已
He's just running late
可能他停下来吃宵夜去了
He probably just stopped for a snack
胖子会饿的  对不对
Fat guys get hungry, right?
对啊
Yeah
灯神信不得
Never trust a genie
已经早上了吗
Morning already?
老天爷啊
Oh, boy
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas
等下
Wait
我看到了拍圣诞照的大好时机
I see a great Christmas photo op
能不能移过来点
Can you move in a little?
说圣诞老人
Say "Santa Claus"
圣诞老人
Santa Claus
我们的第一个圣诞节
Our first Christmas
这个圣诞节就是第一个圣诞节
This Christmas feels like the very first Christmas
第一个圣诞节就是这个圣诞节
The first Christmas is this Christmas
这就是我的第一个圣诞节
'Cause it feels like the first Christmas to me
你说得对  章鱼哥
You were right, Squidward
这个节日就是傻的要命
This is a stupid holiday
可我还是要你收下这个
I still want you to have this
什么
What
这是什么东西
what's this?
礼物
A present
我给你做的  等圣诞老人来你就不会
I made it for you so you wouldn't feel left out when
落单了
Santa came
我
I
就是  我
You know, I
不客气
You're welcome
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
他给我做了个礼物
He made me a present?
大概率是个水母网
It's probably a jellyfish net
或者是个陈年蟹黄堡
Or an old Krabby Patty
或者
Or
是他最爱的内裤
his favorite underpants
什么
What?
啊
Why
看起来好像一根竖笛
it looks like a clarinet
闻起来也像一根竖笛
It smells like one, too
用浮木手工制成
Hand-crafted out of driftwood
章鱼哥
上面还写了我的名字
And it's even got my name on it
按下
这是什么
What's this?
这是我收到过的最棒的礼物了
This is the greatest gift I have ever gotten
我感觉就像个
I feel like a
大浑蛋
Big jerk
我对那可怜的海绵宝宝都做了什么
What have I done to poor SpongeBob?
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
我
I
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
我看我再也用不着这个了
I guess I won't be needing this
好多了
That's better
可怜的小家伙
The poor little guy
他想做的只是传播欢乐而已
All he wanted was to spread a little joy
我最好把这些东西从章鱼哥家拆下来
I better get this stuff off of Squid's place
有人吗
Hello?
谁在那
Who's there?
有人吗
Hello?
啥事
Yes?
谁在那
Who's there?
有人吗
Hello?
快现身
Show yourself
有人吗
Hello?
是谁
Who is it?
就在这上面  你个白痴
Up here, you dunce
我是说
I mean
圣诞快乐  孩子
Merry Christmas, little boy
该不会是
Could it be?
对  就是我
Yes, it is I
圣诞老人
Santa Claus
你就是
You're
圣
San
孩子
Kid?
别激动
Take it easy
圣
San
诞老人
ta
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
圣
San
别再这样了
Don't do that again
我就知道你会来  圣诞老人
I knew you'd make it, Santa
圣诞老人  你的大圆肚子去哪了
Hey, Santa, where's your big, round belly?
那个
Well
这
that
是因为
is a result of
我在海底受到的水压比较大
undersea pressure on my body
你驯鹿哪去了
Where's your reindeer
还有你那会飞的机器呢
and your flying machine?
我把那些都借给复活节兔子了
I loaned them to the Easter bunny
还有这鼻子怎么回事
And what about that nose?
虽然我知道你鼻子本来就很大
I knew you were supposed to have a big one
但是这也太大了吧
but that thing's gigantic
行了
All right
我就是圣诞老人
I'm Santa
圣诞老人
Santa
这是你能给我的最好的礼物了
This is the greatest gift you could have given me
感谢你把圣诞节带来裤头村
Thank you for bringing Christmas to Bikini Bottom
把圣诞节带来裤头村的不是我
I didn't bring Christmas to Bikini Bottom
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
是你带来的
You did
是我带来的
I did?
圣诞快乐  海绵宝宝
Merry Christmas, SpongeBob
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas
真高兴都完事了
I'm glad that's over
你有给我的礼物吗  圣诞老人
Do you have a present for me, Santa?
那个
Well
其实吧  我并不完全是
See, I'm not really
拿礼物吧  圣诞老人
Go ahead, Santa Claus
看到了吧  他货真价实
See, he is real
他让我的圣诞愿望成真了
He made my Christmas wish come true
他不会让你失望的
He won't let you down
没错  等下
Right, just a second
没事  赶紧
Okay, quickly
想想看
Let's see
小女生喜欢啥
What do little girls like?
火柴
A book of matches
还是剃须用品
or a shaving kit?
我出生证明的复印件
A copy of my birth certificate?
这边肯定会有可以给的东西
There's got to be something around here
快想
Think
完美
Perfect
给你  小女生
Here you go, little girl
谢谢圣诞老人
Thanks, Santa
感觉好不错
That almost felt good
我可不
I didn't
都谁啊
Who?
圣诞老人  我礼物呢
Hey, Santa, where's my present?
还有我的
And mine?
那我的呢
And what about me?
看看圣诞老人都给你们送来什么了
Let's see what Santa has for all you good people
使劲想  圣诞老人
Think fast, Santa
给他们的礼物
Gifts for the people
送你碗土豆泥
A bowl of mashed potatoes for you
谢谢圣诞老人
Thank you, Santa
我正好就想要这个
this is just what I wanted
新发型
A new hairstyle
谢谢圣诞老人
Thanks, Santa
给你  派大星
Here you go, Patrick
手表
A wristwatch
谢谢圣诞老人
Thank you, Santa
我当初怎么想的
What was I thinking?
我把我东西全都送走
I gave away all my stuff
就为了海绵宝宝不再伤心
just so SpongeBob wouldn't be sad
我疯了吗
Am I insane?
门你也拿走吧
You might as well take the door
我就只剩这玩意了
It's all that's left
章鱼哥  你把他给错过了
Squidward, you missed him
他刚来了  就像我说的那样
He was here, just like I said
给了我们大家礼物
He gave us all presents
他和蔼可亲  长了个大胡子
He was jolly and he had a beard
鼻子也大  脸颊红润
His nose was big and he had rosy cheeks
特别平易近人
He was friendly and kind
还特别圣诞老人
and Santa-ish
他肚子虽然小
His belly was small
但他的大鼻子充满了圣诞的快乐
but his nose was huge with Christmas joy
他人特好
He was so nice
好了  至少事都成了
Well, at least it's over
这是什么
What's this?
亲爱的章鱼哥
"Dear Squidward
感谢你的所有帮助
"Thanks for all your help
你今年真是个好孩子
"You've been a real good boy this year
温暖的问候
Warm regards
圣诞老人
Santa Claus"
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas
没错
Yup
我疯了
I'm insane
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas
到了  派大星
Ahoy, Patrick
是圣诞岛
it's Christmas Island
礼物就在前方
Presents Ahoy
万岁
Hooray
有暴风雨
A storm
耶
Yay
我是说  不好了
I mean, yikes
要沉下去了
We're going down
把帆收起来
Trim the sails
吊起桅杆
Hoist the yardarms
打开气象频道
Turn on The Weather Channel
派斯
Patchy?
孩子们好
Hi, kids
天哪  海绵宝宝让我可开心了
Boy, that SpongeBob makes me as jolly as a Roger
希望你们都喜欢海绵宝宝的圣诞故事
Well, I hope you enjoyed SpongeBob's Christmas tale
希望你们圣诞节比沉没的宝藏还美好
And I hope your Christmas
is better than sunken treasure
波蒂给我留了个小小的圣诞礼物
Potty left me a little Christmas present
你个槲寄生
Ye old mistletoe
知道这是什么意思吧
And you know what that means
有人该要来亲亲海盗派斯了
Time for somebody to kiss Patchy the Pirate
来啊  谁要来亲
Come on, who's it going to be?
来啊
Come on
给船长亲一口
Kiss the Captain
给咱亲
Give us a kiss
滚  不亲你
No, not you
亲的不是你  波蒂
Not you, Potty
别过来
No
快给我滚
No, get out of here
波蒂别过来
No, Potty
我才不要亲你
I don't want to kiss you
已经说过这回事了
No, we talked about this
波蒂
Potty
亲亲亲亲
Kissy kissy
好吧  看来派斯现在非常忙
Well, it looks like Patchy's pretty busy at the moment
那我来帮他说好了
so I'll say it for him--
晚安
Good night
佳节愉快
and happy holidays
给我亲一口
Give me a kiss